ALAMGIR HOSSAIN

Mechanical Design Engineer | Technical Support Engineer | Web developer | ahopu.github.io

CAREER OBJECTIVE

Professional Mechanical Design Engineer with 1+ years of experience in Computer-Aided Design, Mechanical Drawing, Drafting, Testing, Assembly, Manufacturing, Product Development, and analysis processes to improve overall operational efficiency using Siemens NX, SolidWorks, and AutoCAD. However, I can assure you that I'm a quick learner, adaptive as well as and energetic person.

EDUCATION

Bachelor of Science, Mechanical Design & Manufacturing and Their Automation (2017 – 2021)

University of Chongging University of science and technology, China

- Minor in Comprehensive Chinese
- Total Grade: 81.95% [CGPA: 3.09 out of 5]
- Graduation Project, Reverse design and analysis of automobile storage box (01/2021 04/2021)
- Relevant Courses: Mechanical Design, Machining Equipment, Computer Aided Design, of Mechanical Manufacturing Technology, CNC Machining Technology

SKILLS

- **Programming Languages:** C, HTML, CSS, JavaScript
- Software/Programs: SolidWorks, Siemens NX, AutoCAD, VMS, Microsoft Office, Windows OS
- Professional Skills: Team Leadership, Project Management, Communication, Strong Self-Discipline

EXPERIENCE

Technical Support Engineer

GeoVision Inc., Taipei, Taiwan

- Customer service via e-mail, phone, or remote-control software
- Provide Product training to company staff (sales, engineering, and etc.), customer.
- Tradeshow, roadshow, customer visits support
- Company product information such as specification or related information creation and update
- Company product tutorial creation and update

Mechanical Design Engineer

Jul. 2021 - May. 2022

Aug. 2022 - Present

Xebecware Software Solution & Dhaka, Bangladesh

- Meeting with clients and design teams to determine mechanical applications and requirements.
- Conducting research to inform the design and engineering methods required for the mechanical systems.
- Planning and executing mechanical designs using CAD, CAM, and 3D CAD programs.
- Performing computer simulations and experiments to virtually test and refine the designs.

HOBBIES AND INTEREST

3D Modeling, Football, Cycling, Traveling, Movies, Gaming, TV-Series, Blogging, Coding.







